♪ In the face of turbulence ♪
♪ 난기류 앞에서 ♪
♪ Your roots are firm ♪
♪당신의 뿌리는 확고합니다 ♪
♪ To this piece of land ♪
♪ 이 땅으로 ♪
♪ Chasing the flow of the waves ♪
♪파도의 흐름을 쫓아 ♪
♪ The fallen leaves ♪
♪낙엽이 ♪
♪ The horizon ♪
♪ 지평선 ♪
♪ Split Away ♪
♪ 갈라져 ♪
♪ At the end of the world ♪
♪ 세상의 끝에서 ♪
♪ It's forever ♪
♪영원해요 ♪
♪ When we met and parted ♪
♪ 만나고 헤어질 때 ♪
♪ When we depend on each other ♪ ♪ and we move away ♪
♪우리가 서로 의지하고 ♪ ♪우리가 멀어질 때 ♪
♪ I never forgot ♪
♪나는 결코 잊지 않았다 ♪
♪ I cross the edge of the sword ♪
♪ 나는 칼날을 넘었다 ♪
♪ Crossing the starry sky ♪
♪ 별하늘을 건너 ♪
♪ Falling dreams ♪
♪ 떨어지는 꿈 ♪
♪ Walk with me to tell the story of the wind ♪
♪ 나와 함께 걸으며 바람의 이야기를 들려주세요 ♪
♪ The wind blows its waves ♪
♪바람이 파도를 분다 ♪
♪ I see the thousands of candles cross ♪
♪ 수천 개의 촛불이 교차하는 것이 보입니다 ♪
♪ The vast land and the boundless sea ♪
♪ 광활한 대지와 끝없는 바다 ♪
♪ Red clothes flying high ♪
♪빨간 옷이 높이 날아오르네 ♪
♪ In the face of bitterness, sadness ♪ ♪ Emotion and happy adventure ♪
♪ 괴로움과 슬픔 앞에서 ♪ ♪ 감동과 행복한 모험 ♪
♪ I just hope you're by my side ♪
♪당신이 내 곁에 있기를 바라요 ♪
♪ I just want you to be by my side ♪
♪나는 단지 당신이 내 곁에 있기를 바랍니다 ♪
♪ Like an interconnected tower ♪ ♪ I will accompany you until the end ♪
♪ 서로 연결된 탑처럼 ♪ ♪ 끝까지 동행하겠습니다 ♪
♪ Seeing the fireflies that fill our shoulders ♪ ♪ On our shoulders ♪
♪어깨를 가득 채운 반딧불이를 보며 ♪ ♪어깨에 ♪
♪ I don't regret it, I have no doubts ♪
♪후회하지 않아, 의심하지 않아 ♪
= Wonderland of Love =
= 사랑의 이상한 나라 =
= Episode 17 =
= 17회 =
Let's go.
갑시다.
You still haven't recovered.
당신은 아직 회복되지 않았습니다.
So don't drink anymore.
그러니 더 이상 술을 마시지 마세요.
When I think about it,
생각해보면,
when I think
내가 생각할 때
in Tai Qing Palace.
태청궁에서.
It must be.
그래야 합니다.
Ying,
잉,
Are you still mad at me?
넌 아직도 나 한테 화났어?
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
They fought.
그들은 싸웠다.
It's just a love fight.
그냥 사랑싸움이에요.
They will reconcile after the fight.
그들은 싸움 후에 화해할 것이다.
And also,
그리고 또한,
even if they fight,
그들이 싸워도,
seu Sr.shiqi
스시치 선생님
really lose?
정말 졌어?
Let's not bother them.
그들을 괴롭히지 말자.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Where will we go?
어디로 갈까요?
I'm a little hungry.
조금 배가 고파요.
Why don't we go
우리 가는 게 어때?
at Tang convenience store?
탕편의점에서?
I always heard
난 항상 들었어
that their snacks
그들의 간식은
famous in Dongdu.
동두에서 유명해요.
Must be delicious.
맛있을 것 같아요.
I want to go try it.
가서 해보고 싶어요.
Come, I'll take you.
오세요, 제가 데려가겠습니다.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Have your fingers improved?
손가락이 좋아졌나요?
The chess pieces are ready.
체스 조각이 준비되었습니다.
My fingers will recover.
손가락이 회복될 거예요.
You made a whole set of chess pieces
당신은 체스 말 전체 세트를 만들었습니다
for your lord.
당신의 주를 위해.
You even ignored
넌 심지어 무시했지
your fingers hurt.
손가락이 아프다.
But you never did
하지만 넌 그런 적이 없어
for me.
나를 위한.
Who said I never did anything for you?
내가 당신을 위해 아무것도 한 적이 없다고 누가 말했습니까?
What did you do for me?
당신은 나를 위해 무엇을 했나요?
Yourself
당신 자신
Did you do it?
너 그거 했니?
When I was at Tong Pass,
제가 통고개에 있었을 때,
I did this when I was at Tong Pass.
통고개에 있을 때 이런 일을 했어요.
I wanted to find an opportunity
기회를 찾고 싶었어요
to give you
당신에게 주기 위해
But then I discovered
그런데 나는 발견했다.
you are an ungrateful person
당신은 배은망덕한 사람이에요
nor does it help those in need.
도움이 필요한 사람들에게도 도움이 되지 않습니다.
I better burn.
나는 타는 것이 낫다.
You can't burn.
당신은 태울 수 없습니다.
If you're not angry...
화내지 않으면...
If you're not angry,
화가 나지 않는다면,
even if you scolded me
네가 나를 꾸짖었어도
Countless times a day,
하루에도 수없이,
I'm going to listen.
나는 들어볼 것이다.
Who will scold you?
누가 당신을 꾸짖겠습니까?
I'll put it up for you to see.
보실 수 있도록 올려드리겠습니다.
It's hard to do with one hand.
한손으로 하기 힘드네요.
Can you help me?
도와주세요?
It's not tight enough.
충분히 빡빡하지 않습니다.
Look.
바라보다.
Otherwise, you are giving away free for nothing.
그렇지 않으면, 당신은 아무 것도 없이 공짜로 주는 것입니다 .
Let me see.
어디 보자.
No final,
최종 없음,
We are enemies, not friends.
우리는 친구가 아니라 적입니다.
When we meet again
우리가 다시 만날때
and we meet again,
그리고 우리는 다시 만난다,
I fear that on the battlefield
전장에서 그럴까봐 두렵다
fight for our lives.
우리의 삶을 위해 싸워라.
Shiqi,
시치,
Careful.
주의 깊은.
Where's the ear?
귀는 어디에 있나요?
He's already passed out.
그는 이미 기절했습니다.
I pierced him a few more times.
나는 그를 몇 번 더 찔렀습니다.
He just woke up he won't wake up.
그 사람은 방금 일어났는데, 일어나지 않을 거예요.
It's really cruel.
정말 잔인해요.
He taught me well.
그는 나에게 잘 가르쳐주었다.
Excuse me sir.
실례합니다.
Lord, take us to the other side.
주님, 우리를 반대편으로 데려가 주십시오.
The faster the better.
빠를수록 좋습니다.
Press.
누르다.
Lord Qin?
진 경?
Are you calling me?
나한테 전화하는 거야?
Mister Qin, that was a great strategy.
진 씨, 그것은 훌륭한 전략이었습니다.
I was just planning.
나는 단지 계획하고 있었다.
When I saw the recipe that Taozi
타오즈가 만든 레시피를 보니
taozi gave it to Chang 'er that day,
그날 도자가 장어에게 주었더니
I had already suspected something.
나는 이미 뭔가를 의심하고 있었습니다.
As I already suspected,
이미 의심했던 대로,
you not only made contact
너만 연락한 게 아니잖아
with the Cui army through the pharmacy,
약국을 통해 Cui 군대와 함께
and even acted.
그리고 심지어 행동까지 했다.
Everything to make Chang'er believe
Chang'er를 믿게 만드는 모든 것
Taozi spoke well of me.
Taozi는 나에 대해 좋게 말했습니다.
You have been persuaded.
당신은 설득되었습니다.
It was just to arrange a meal
단지 식사를 준비하기 위해서였을 뿐입니다
to sting me and run away.
나를 찌르고 도망가려고.
So you always knew
그래서 당신은 항상 알고 있었죠
you always accompanied us.
당신은 항상 우리와 동행했습니다.
I know you well.
나는 너를 잘 알아.
If I didn't let you try to escape,
만약 내가 당신이 탈출을 시도하도록 두지 않았다면,
How would you be happy?
어떻게 행복할까요?
He is well.
그는 건강하다.
I'll take you back
나는 당신을 다시 데려 갈 것이다
to your house.
당신 집으로.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Governor,
지사,
the envoy we sent to Cui's army
우리가 최나라 군대에 보낸 사절
was whipped by Cui Yi
최이에게 채찍질당했다
before being sent back here.
여기로 다시 보내지기 전에.
Cuiyi's temperament
추이의 기질
still the same.
여전히 동일합니다.
The vanguard of the Cui Army
추이군의 선봉대
arrived at the entrance of Jiuqu.
주취(Jiuqu) 입구에 도착했다.
It looks like they want to cross the river.
그들은 강을 건너고 싶어하는 것 같습니다.
If Cui Yi cross or river
최이가 건너거나 강을 건너면
to besiege and attack Xichang,
서창(西昌)을 포위하고 공격한다.
there will be riots in the capital
수도에서 폭동이 일어날 것이다
I'm afraid it could disrupt the overall situation.
전반적인 상황을 혼란에 빠뜨릴까 두렵습니다 .
Governor,
지사,
Don't you think we should while they were crossing
그들이 건너는 동안 우리가 그래야 한다고 생각하지 않니?
cross the river.
강을 건너다.
Cuyi has always been cunning.
Cuyi는 항상 교활했습니다.
If he had the courage to cross the river at the entrance to Jiuqu,
만일 그가 구곡(九曲) 입구에서 강을 건너는 용기가 있었다면 ,
he must have considered
그 사람도 고려했을 텐데
Shallow waters.
얕은 물.
It's easy to cross the river,
강을 건너는 것은 쉽습니다.
no,
아니요,
he will not cross the river
그는 강을 건너지 않을 것이다
will not cross the river.
강을 건너지 못할 것이다.
He must be diverting attention.
그 사람이 관심을 돌리고 있는 게 틀림없어요.
Could it be that Cui Yi's son
최이의 아들이 아닐까?
Wasn't he intercepted and killed?
가로채서 죽인거 아닌가요?
It seems this time
이번엔 그런 것 같다
his goal is not Xichang.
그의 목표는 Xichang이 아닙니다.
Let's let him cross the river.
그가 강을 건너도록 합시다.
Mayor,
시장,
If the Cui army crosses the river and helps Li Ni...
최군이 강을 건너 리니를 도우면...
I said let him cross the river.
나는 그에게 강을 건너게 하라고 말했습니다.
If he dares to attack Xichang
만약 그가 감히 시창을 공격한다면
to attack Xichang
시창을 공격하다
and fight him to the death.
그리고 그와 죽을 때까지 싸워라.
He is heading to Luoyang,
뤄양(洛陽)으로 향하고 있다.
I will send troops
병력을 보내겠다
to seize the opportunity li Ni.
기회를 잡으려고 리니.
Be careful, it's hot.
조심하세요. 뜨거워요.
Taozi,
타오지,
How is Lieutenant He's health?
허 중위님 건강은 어떤가요?
Do you need medicinal herbs?
약초가 필요합니까?
I'm glad Your Highness
반가워요 전하
we have no shortage of medicinal herbs,
우리에겐 약초가 부족하지 않습니다.
I believe you know
나는 당신이 알고 있다고 믿습니다
of your provocation
당신의 도발
made Lieutenant He's illness worse.
중위의 병을 더욱 악화시켰습니다.
How bad.
얼마나 나쁜지.
How about I say something
내가 한마디 하면 어때?
to keep her alive.
그녀를 살려두기 위해.
After this lesson,
이 수업이 끝난 후,
I sent several heavy troops
나는 중무장한 병력을 여러 명 보냈습니다.
to surround the Tai Qing Palace inside and outside the palace,
태청궁을 궁궐 안팎으로 둘러싸도록 하고,
out and in.
밖으로 그리고 안으로.
I also sent dozens of observers
관찰자도 수십 명 보냈는데
to watch each exit.
각 출구를 감시합니다.
If you still want to escape,
그래도 탈출하고 싶다면,
I will be nervous for you.
나는 당신 때문에 긴장할 것입니다.
Mr Qin,
진 씨,
I believe you already planned everything
나는 당신이 이미 모든 것을 계획했다고 믿습니다
for a safe attack
안전한 공격을 위해
em Xichang.
em 시창.
No matter how complete the plan is,
아무리 계획이 완벽해도
there will be failures.
실패가있을 것입니다.
How can we talk about being thorough
철저한 것에 대해 어떻게 이야기 할 수 있습니까?
or ensure certain success?
아니면 확실한 성공을 보장하시겠습니까?
Since we don't have a complete plan,
아직 완전한 계획이 없기 때문에
how about that?
어떻게에 대한?
I'll do it for you,
내가 해줄게
after killing Sun Jing,
손징을 죽인 후
and you let me go.
그리고 당신은 나를 놓아주었습니다.
Then,
그 다음에,
not worth it.
그럴 가치가 없어.
So it's not worth it.
따라서 그럴 가치가 없습니다.
I didn't imagine that
그건 상상도 못했는데
that you gave me so much value.
당신이 나에게 너무 많은 가치를 주었다고.
A woman like me
나 같은 여자
worth more than Sun Jin?
선진보다 더 가치있어?
Cui Yi's only daughter
추이의 외동딸
It is naturally more valuable than Sun Jin.
당연히 선진보다 더 가치가 있다 .
So you already knew she was the general's daughter?
그럼 당신은 그 사람이 장군의 딸이라는 걸 이미 알고 있었나요 ?
So you already know.
그래서 당신은 이미 알고 있습니다.
It's no wonder that
당연하지
you won't let me go.
당신은 나를 놓아주지 않을 것입니다.
Miss Taozi,
미스 타오지,
Can you go out for a bit?
잠깐 나가볼 수 있나요?
I have some words
말이 좀 있어요
to say
말하다
to Lieutenant He.
그 중위에게.
In fact, after saving you,
사실은 널 구하고 나서
I wrote a letter
나는 편지를 썼다
for General Cui.
추이 장군을 위해.
General Cui
추이 장군
it turns out we were close we were close by.
우리는 가까이에 있었다는 것이 밝혀졌습니다 .
It's a shame we arrived late
우리가 늦게 도착해서 유감이야
and Mr. Cui fell into the river.
그리고 Cui 씨는 강에 빠졌습니다.
But now that we've rescued Ying,
하지만 이제 우리가 잉을 구출했으니,
don't worry.
괜찮아요.
Ying is safe.
잉은 안전해요.
He is recovering in Zhenxi barracks.
그는 Zhenxi 막사에서 회복 중입니다.
I sincerely hope you can lead your army
진심으로 당신이 군대를 이끌 수 있기를 바랍니다
to join Zhenxi, capture Xichang together,
Zhenxi에 합류하고 함께 Xichang을 점령하고
to finish off Sun Jin. To suppress the rebellion.
선진을 끝내려고. 반란을 진압하기 위해.
Until then, your pearl in the palm of your hand
그때까지 너의 진주는 너의 손바닥 안에
your pearl in the palm of your hand.
당신의 손바닥에 진주가 있습니다.
I told you you're fine.
나는 당신이 괜찮다고 말했어요.
I sincerely beg him
진심으로 그분께 간청합니다
join me in suppressing the Crook Sun
나와 함께 Crook Sun을 진압하세요
and recover Xichang.
그리고 시창을 회복하세요.
Although General Cui responded to my letter,
최장군이 내 편지에 답했지만,
but...
하지만...
What do you mean, Your Highness?
무슨 뜻입니까, 전하?
Be honest.
솔직하게 말하세요.
I finally discovered
드디어 발견했어요
the heroine who led women to fight fought to the death in Yingzhou
여성들을 투쟁으로 이끈 여주인공은 영주에서 목숨을 걸고 싸웠다
your mother
당신의 어머니
And his mother.
그리고 그의 어머니.
Heroica's surname is He.
Heroica의 성은 He입니다.
So you changed your last name
그래서 성을 바꾸셨군요
and say that he belongs to the He clan.
그가 He 씨족에 속한다고 말합니다.
These days, these days.
요즘 요즘.
The heroine is such a brave figure.
여주인공은 정말 용감한 인물이에요.
General Cui is also extraordinary
추이 장군 도 대단하다
have a daughter like you.
당신 같은 딸이 있어요.
Are you investigating?
조사 중인가요?
Sim.
심.
I do not know anything
나는 아무것도 모른다
about Great General Cui.
추이 장군에 대해.
So I can only ask for this method.
그래서 이 방법만 부탁드릴 수 있겠네요.
Perhaps
아마도
after some time,
몇 시간 후,
you will know what kind of person
어떤 사람인지 알게 될 거야
my father.
내 아버지.
I have a bad feeling about this.
나는 이것에 대해 나쁜 느낌을 가지고 있습니다.
Why?
왜?
I always feel that
나는 항상 그것을 느낀다
that he is like you.
그 사람도 너와 같다고.
Intelligent,
지능적인,
and extremely powerful.
그리고 매우 강력합니다.
I don't know how he will react
그 사람이 어떻게 반응할지 모르겠어요
how he will react.
그가 어떻게 반응할지.
I am my father's only daughter.
나는 아버지의 유일한 딸입니다.
You used me to pressure you.
당신은 나를 이용하여 당신에게 압력을 가했습니다.
I need to tell you
당신에게 말해야 해요
How will he react?
그는 어떻게 반응할까요?
If you fall into his hands,
만약 당신이 그의 손에 넘어간다면,
It is likely that
가능성이 높습니다
he will whip you.
그는 당신을 채찍질할 것이다.
So I'll have to be careful
그러니 조심해야겠습니다
don't fall into his hand.
그의 손에 빠지지 마십시오.
Grande General,
그란데 장군,
the vanguard has already crossed the river.
선봉대는 이미 강을 건넜습니다.
It's time for the middle army It's time to attack.
이제 중군이 공격할 시간이다.
This mentor
이 멘토
is hidden in Luoyang.
뤄양에 숨겨져 있어요.
And you dared to kill my son.
그리고 당신은 감히 내 아들을 죽이려고 했어요.
The Cui army
추이군
Will retaliate.
보복할 것이다.
Like this?
이와 같이?
Doesn't Cui Yi have a son?
최이에게는 아들이 없나요?
Has a daughter?
딸이 있나요?
Is Lieutenant He Cui Lin?
허추이린(He Cui Lin) 중위인가요?
The one who died
죽은 사람
Was it just a hoax?
그냥 사기였나요?
It can not be.
그럴 수 없다.
Absolutely impossible.
절대 불가능합니다.
Shiqi,
시치,
you are lying to me
당신은 나에게 거짓말을하고 있습니다
to lie to me
나에게 거짓말을 하려고
so I can marry her?
그럼 내가 그 사람과 결혼할 수 있을까?
Think carefully
잘 생각 해봐
Mr. Cui's attitude
추이 씨의 태도
com to Tenente He.
Tenente He로 오세요.
Also, think about it
또한, 생각해 보세요.
if I want to deceive you.
내가 당신을 속이고 싶다면.
I understood.
나는 이해했다.
That's why,
그렇기 때문에,
you kept her trapped
당신은 그녀를 가둬두었어요
locked her
그녀를 잠갔다
and sent a great army.
그리고 큰 군대를 보냈습니다.
Do you want to use it to pressure Cuyi?
Cuyi에게 압력을 가하는 데 사용하시겠습니까 ?
That's not pressuring him.
그것은 그에게 압력을 가하는 것이 아닙니다.
Cui Yi,
추이,
para o grande general Pingliang, Cui Yi.
para o grande 장군 Pingliang, Cui Yi.
To think about the Zhenxi army
Zhenxi 군대에 대해 생각하려면
to save his daughter,
딸을 구하기 위해,
I asked him to join us
나는 그에게 우리와 함께 하자고 요청했다
to calm the rebellion
반란을 진정시키기 위해
to recover Xichang.
시창을 회복하기 위해.
Come take the medicine.
약을 드세요.
For you.
당신을 위한.
The flowers that Mister Qin sent today
오늘 진 선생님이 보낸 꽃
they are so beautiful.
정말 아름다워요.
Because today
왜냐면 오늘
different today?
오늘은 달라?
How different?
얼마나 다른가요?
As if you had changed
마치 당신이 변한 것처럼
like always.
늘 그렇듯.
I'm just thinking
난 그냥 생각 중이야
that in some days,
그건 언젠가는,
maybe I can
아마 할 수 있을 거야
to my father's side.
아버지 곁으로.
If I don't get well,
내가 몸이 안 좋아지면,
Won't he be more worried?
그 사람이 더 걱정하지 않을까?
Have you thought of a way out of here?
여기서 나갈 방법은 생각해 봤어 ?
I think our father once led the army
내 생각엔 우리 아버지가 한때 군대를 이끌었던 것 같아
and arrived outside of Luoyang.
낙양 외곽에 도착했습니다.
The situation is changing rapidly.
상황은 빠르게 변화하고 있습니다.
Li Ni
리니
You won't be able to keep us for long.
당신은 우리를 오래 보관할 수 없습니다.
That is great.
그거 좋네.
I was just thinking
난 그냥 생각하고 있었어요
if the Young Master
만약 영 마스터라면
escape safely,
무사히 탈출하고,
it would be really good.
정말 좋을 것 같아요.
Otherwise,
그렇지 않으면,
I will regret it forever.
나는 그것을 영원히 후회할 것이다.
Don't be sad.
슬퍼하지 마세요.
If Young Master knew,
영스승님이 알았다면,
I would also expect that
나 역시 그럴 것이라고 예상한다.
Don't you think too much,
너무 많이 생각하지 마세요.
to take care of yourself.
자신을 돌보기 위해.
The living must cherish their lives.
살아있는 사람은 자신의 생명을 소중히 여겨야 합니다.
It's the greatest comfort
최고의 편안함이에요
for the deceased.
고인을 위해.
That's what my father told me
아버지가 나한테 그러셨어.
the mother sacrificed herself for the city.
어머니는 도시를 위해 자신을 희생했습니다.
Mister shiqi, there is news. Sun Jing actually mobilized his troops.
시치씨, 소식이 있어요. Sun Jing은 실제로 군대를 동원했습니다.
And divided them in two.
그리고 둘로 나누었습니다.
One heads to Luoyang,
하나는 낙양(洛陽)으로 향하고,
and the other goes straight to the main camp.
다른 하나는 메인 캠프로 곧장 이동합니다.
Exactly as you predicted.
당신이 예측한 것과 똑같습니다.
That scoundrel Sun Jing
그 악당 쑨징
is enjoying
즐기고 있다
o ataque de Cui Yi a Luoyang
o ataque de Cui Yi a Luoyang
to send troops to attack the Zhenxi army.
Zhenxi 군대를 공격하기 위해 군대를 파견합니다 .
And sent troops
그리고 군대를 보냈다.
for our family.
우리 가족을 위해.
It seems like he really wants to seize the opportunity.
그는 정말로 기회를 잡고 싶어하는 것 같습니다 .
So we'll attack them here first, and catch them off guard.
그러니 우리는 먼저 이곳을 공격 하고 방심하지 않을 것입니다.
The weather is getting cold now.
이제 날씨가 추워지고 있습니다.
Where did these flowers come from?
이 꽃들은 어디서 왔나요?
Mr. Qin didn't send
진 씨가 보내지 않았어요
to send flowers every day?
매일 꽃을 보내려고?
So I took the petals
그래서 꽃잎을 따왔어
and flower buds.
그리고 꽃봉오리.
Then, those that suit will be used
그런 다음 적합한 것을 사용합니다 .
and the others can be used for bathing.
나머지는 목욕에 사용할 수 있습니다.
No waste.
낭비가 없습니다.
Our Taozi
우리의 도자
doesn't care about problems.
문제에는 관심이 없습니다.
Stay here every day
매일 여기에 머물러 라.
It's very boring.
매우 지루합니다.
We have to find something to do.
우리는 할 일을 찾아야 합니다.
Before Mr Qin sent by Mr Qin
Mr Qin 이 Mr Qin을 보내기 전
They are really cool.
그들은 정말 멋지다.
Mr He,
허 씨,
I think that
내 생각에는
you look very good
너 정말 좋아 보인다
like this.
이와 같이.
Do you really like that
당신은 그것을 정말로 좋아합니까?
like such a beautiful girl.
정말 아름다운 소녀처럼.
But, Lieutenant He,
그런데 그 중위님,
You look brave too.
당신 도 용감해 보이네요.
But you don't dress like that
그런데 넌 그런 옷은 입지 않잖아
every day.
매일.
I still think you
나는 아직도 당신을 생각
The most beautiful.
가장 아름다운.
Why hasn't Mister Qin arrived yet?
진 씨는 왜 아직 도착하지 않았나요?
I think
제 생각에는
he must have been
그는 그랬음에 틀림없어
for something.
뭔가를 위해.
Perhaps
아마도
My father has already arrived.
아버지는 이미 도착하셨습니다.
Luoyang City really needs to step up.
뤄양시는 정말로 나서야 합니다.
Every moment that lasts is a moment gained.
지속되는 모든 순간은 얻은 순간입니다.
Se Luoyang cair,
세뤄양 카이어,
Sun Jing's forces
손징의 군대
they will soon join them,
그들은 곧 그들과 합류할 것이다.
joining them.
그들과 합류합니다.
If that happen,
만약 그런 일이 일어난다면,
it will be a problem.
문제가 될 것입니다.
Youdao,
유다오,
let's make a bet.
내기하자.
What?
무엇?
Let's bet on how long
얼마나 오래 걸릴지 내기하자
luoyang can last.
낙양은 지속될 수 있습니다.
I won't bet with you.
나는 당신과 내기하지 않을 것입니다.
Temoque a Luoyang
테모크 아 뤄양
may not last long.
오래 가지 못할 수도 있습니다.
What a bunch of idiots.
정말 바보 같군요.
We can only wait
우리는 기다릴 수 밖에 없어
cui Yi possa atrasar a Sun Jing.
Cui Yi Possa는 Sun Jing과 관련이 있습니다.
Serious?
심각한?
The Great General is here.
위대한 장군님이 여기 계십니다.
It's a guess.
추측입니다.
But it is quite possible.
그러나 그것은 가능합니다.
During these years, the Cui Army in the name of the prince,
이 기간 동안 최군은 왕자의 이름으로
in the name of the Young Master.
젊은 스승의 이름으로.
My father is in Yingzhou in Yingzhou.
나의 아버지는 잉저우의 잉저우에 계십니다.
But every time he acts,
하지만 그가 행동할 때마다
he crushes Sun Jing's army.
그는 Sun Jing의 군대를 분쇄합니다.
Li Ni is very cunning.
Li Ni는 매우 교활합니다.
He can't understand
그는 이해할 수 없다
the father's method.
아버지의 방법.
So he won't do anything reckless.
그래서 그는 무모한 짓을 하지 않을 것이다.
What does Lord Qin want to do?
진경은 무엇을 하고 싶나요?
He wants to go to war wants to go to war?
그는 전쟁에 가고 싶어 전쟁에 가고 싶어?
Let's attack the enemy
적을 공격하자
and then fight the enemy.
그런 다음 적과 싸우십시오.
At Li Ni's priority
Li Ni를 최우선으로
It's winning over the father.
아버지를 이기는 것입니다.
To form an alliance,
동맹을 맺기 위해서는,
recover Xichang,
시창을 회복하고,
and protect the Li family kingdom.
리 가문의 왕국을 보호하세요.
Li Ni
리니
He's very arrogant.
그는 매우 거만해요.
Miss,
놓치다,
do not say anything.
아무것도 말 하지마.
When the general comes,
장군님 오시면
we have to hit him
우리는 그 사람을 때려야 해
to vent our frustration.
우리의 좌절감을 해소하기 위해.
Don't worry,
괜찮아요,
I won't say anything to him.
나는 그에게 아무 말도 하지 않을 것이다.
And also,
그리고 또한,
when my father is a notable figure,
아버지가 주목할만한 인물일 때,
when my father is a notable figure?
우리 아버지가 주목할만한 인물이라면?
Shiqi,
시치,
our prisoners are housed.
우리 죄수들은 수용되어 있습니다.
Some injured soldiers
일부 부상당한 군인들
were also treated.
치료도 받았습니다.
This battle
이 전투
made our some victims to Sun Jing.
우리를 Sun Jing에게 희생자로 만들었습니다.
Sr. shiqi.
시치 씨.
(Fengtai Gate)
(펑타이 게이트)
Stormed the Fengtai Gate at around 3pm.
오후 3시쯤 펑타이문(Fengtai Gate)을 습격했습니다.
No news yet
아직 소식이 없습니다
of Lord Xin, Lord Qi and the Emperor.
Xin 신, Qi 신 및 황제의.
Furthermore,
뿐만 아니라,
Cui Yi also sent someone to send a letter.
Cui Yi도 누군가를 보내 편지를 보냈습니다.
I am serving His Majesty, Lord Xin and Mr. Qi in Luoyang.
나는 낙양에서 신 폐하와 치 선생을 섬기고 있습니다.
To show my sincerity,
진심을 보여드리기 위해,
to show my sincerity. From the Cui Army.
내 진심을 보여주기 위해. 추이군(Cui Army) 출신.
If not, we will see you in battle.
그렇지 않다면 전투에서 뵙겠습니다.
Like father, like daughter.
아버지처럼, 딸처럼.
They refuse to suffer any losses.
그들은 어떤 손실도 입는 것을 거부합니다.
Your Highness,
전하,
please have some tea.
차 좀 드세요.
For you.
당신을 위한.
Thanks.
감사해요.
Are you still using the device?
아직도 그 기기를 사용하고 계시나요?
Sim.
심.
The silver needle to remove the silver needle.
은 바늘을 제거하는 은 바늘 입니다.
After that,
이후,
I never took it off again.
나는 다시는 그것을 벗지 않았습니다.
You even only have one device.
장치가 하나만 있는 경우도 있습니다.
Your Highness, why are you acting like this?
전하, 왜 이런 행동을 하시나요?
If anyone wants to give me another one,
누군가 나에게 또 하나를 주고 싶다면 ,
I don't mind accepting.
나는 받아들이는 것을 꺼리지 않는다.
Despise your busy military affairs,
바쁜 군사 업무를 경멸하고
you came here.
당신은 여기에 왔습니다.
My father must have
아버지가 꼭 갖고 계실 거에요
He has already shown you his sincerity.
그는 이미 당신에게 그의 진심을 보여주었습니다.
Before,
전에,
I was curious
나는 궁금했어
your personality.
당신의 성격.
He is exactly as I imagined.
그 사람은 내가 상상했던 바로 그 사람이다.
You two
너희 둘
are almost the same.
거의 동일합니다.
You really are his daughter.
당신은 정말로 그의 딸입니다.
And he is your father.
그리고 그는 당신의 아버지입니다.
Like this?
이와 같이?
Your father
아버지
captured effortlessly
여유롭게 캡처
without major difficulties.
큰 어려움 없이.
My father and my two older brothers
아버지와 두 형
were captured by their father.
아버지에게 붙잡혔습니다.
My father is generous and courteous.
나의 아버지는 관대하고 예의바릅니다.
I believe the emperor
나는 황제를 믿는다
will thank you very much.
정말 감사하겠습니다.
So tell me,
그러니 나에게 말해봐,
your face is so beautiful.
당신의 얼굴은 정말 아름다워요.
You look more like dad
넌 아빠를 더 닮았어
or your mother?
아니면 네 엄마?
I hope you don't think that
나는 당신이 그렇게 생각하지 않기를 바랍니다
that these sweet words
이 달콤한 말은
will make me forget
나를 잊게 만들거야
of his prison.
그의 감옥.
Your father is so generous.
네 아버지는 참 관대하시구나.
I dare not force you to stay any longer.
나는 감히 당신에게 더 이상 머물도록 강요하지 않습니다.
It's just...
그것은 단지 ...
Who knows when and where it will be
언제 어디서 일어날지 누가 알겠어요?
the next time we meet.
다음에 만날 때.
When you go
당신이 갈 때
let me go?
날 보내줘?
Great General Cui wrote a letter
최대장군이 편지를 썼다
He wants to see you tomorrow.
그는 내일 당신을 만나고 싶어합니다.
How could I not agree?
내가 어떻게 동의하지 않을 수 있겠는가?
Tomorrow?
내일?
It's too early, isn't it?
너무 이르지 않나요?
Give it time.
시간을 주세요.
Did you really do that?
정말 그랬나요?
Can you really hear?
정말 들리나요?
From now on, as long as you blow,
이제부터 불기만 하면
I will find you immediately.
즉시 찾아드리겠습니다.
I am here.
나는 여기 있다.
What...
무엇...
What it was?
그게 뭐였지?
Not satisfied?
만족스럽지 않으신가요?
I really like.
나는 정말 좋아한다.
I just want to eat some pig ear.
그냥 돼지 귀 좀 먹고 싶은데요.
I'll buy it for you.
내가 사줄게.
Don't be sad,
슬퍼하지 마세요.
I will be back soon.
금방 돌아 올게요.
What it was?
그게 뭐였지?
Tomorrow I'm leaving.
내일 나는 떠날 것이다.
Will you really
정말 그럴까요?
buy pig ears?
돼지 귀를 살까?
But...
하지만...
You said you wanted to eat.
먹고 싶다고 하셨어요.
You really are
당신은 정말로
really so stupid.
정말 바보같아.
I am here.
나는 여기 있다.
Shiqi,
시치,
you didn't say that
당신은 그런 말을하지 않았습니다
the army is heavy
군대는 무겁다
and many observers are watching here?
많은 관찰자들이 여기를 지켜보고 있나요?
Sim.
심.
Then,
그 다음에,
if we leave here in silence,
우리가 여기서 조용히 떠나면
Will anyone notice?
누구든지 알아차릴 수 있을까요?
We will try.
우리가해볼 게요.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Let's see who gets to the stable first.
누가 마구간에 먼저 도착하는지 봅시다.
He is well.
그는 건강하다.
♪ In this turbulence ♪
♪ 이 난기류 속에서 ♪
♪ Your roots are firm ♪ ♪ On this piece of land ♪
♪ 너의 뿌리는 굳건하다 ♪ ♪ 이 땅 위에 ♪
♪ Chasing the waves ♪
♪ 파도를 쫓아 ♪
♪ Leaves flutter on the horizon ♪
♪ 지평선에 나뭇잎이 펄럭인다 ♪
♪ Looking away ♪
♪ 멀리 바라보며 ♪
♪ The end of the world is eternity ♪
♪ 세상의 종말은 영원이다 ♪
Who's there?
거기 누구 있어요?
♪ When we depend on each other ♪ ♪ and we move away ♪
♪우리가 서로 의지하고 ♪ ♪우리가 멀어질 때 ♪
- Your Highness. -His highness.
- 전하.
♪ The wind blows the cut swords ♪
♪베어진 검에 바람이 분다 ♪
♪ Crossing the starry sky ♪
♪ 별하늘을 건너 ♪
♪ The dream falls and scatters in the wind ♪
♪ 꿈은 바람에 흩어진다 ♪
You lost.
당신은 잃었습니다.
♪ The wind blows the waves ♪
♪ 바람이 파도를 분다 ♪
♪ I see thousands of sails crossing each other ♪ The vast land and the vast sea ♪
♪ 수천 개의 돛이 서로 교차하는 것이 보입니다 ♪ 광활한 땅과 광활한 바다 ♪
♪ Red clothes flying high ♪
♪빨간 옷이 높이 날아오르네 ♪
I don't know who it will be
누가 될지는 모르겠지만
The winner in this case.
이 경우 승자입니다.
So let's keep playing.
그럼 계속 플레이해 볼까요?
To see who gets to Wonderland first.
누가 먼저 이상한 나라에 도착하는지 확인하기 위해.
♪ Like a lightning bolt of a tree ♪ With interconnected roots ♪
♪ 나무의 번개처럼 ♪ 서로 연결된 뿌리로 ♪
♪ I will accompany you until the end ♪
♪끝까지 동행하겠습니다♪
♪ Facing wind and rain together ♪ With a happy smile ♪
♪ 비바람과 함께 ♪ 행복한 미소로 ♪
♪ I don't regret it, I have no doubts ♪
♪후회하지 않아, 의심하지 않아 ♪
♪ The old road at sunset ♪
♪해질녘의 옛길 ♪
♪ I will accompany you until the end ♪
♪끝까지 동행하겠습니다♪
♪ Seeing the fireflies that fill our shoulders ♪ ♪ On our shoulders ♪
♪어깨를 가득 채운 반딧불이를 보며 ♪ ♪어깨에 ♪
♪ I don't regret it, I have no doubts ♪
♪후회하지 않아, 의심하지 않아 ♪
Look at the capital of Wonderland
이상한 나라의 수도를 보세요
It's really beautiful.
정말 아름답습니다.
Look.
바라보다.
I always wanted to know
난 항상 알고 싶었어요
How did you discover my identity?
내 정체를 어떻게 알게 됐나요?
Miss behavior
미스 행동
not an ordinary person can understand.
평범한 사람은 이해할 수 없습니다.
No one ever suspected
아무도 의심한 적 없어
my identity and my relationship
나의 정체성과 나의 관계
with Young Master before.
전에 Young Master와 함께.
Because you
당신 때문에
Did you undersand?
이해했나요?
When you lied to me
당신이 나에게 거짓말을 했을 때
being Mr. Cui's concubine,
최 씨의 첩이 되어
I began to suspect his identity.
나는 그의 정체를 의심하기 시작했다.
So I organized a banquet
그래서 연회를 준비했어요
to test Mr Cui.
Cui 씨를 테스트하기 위해.
This only confirms
이것만 확인
his identity was not simple.
그의 정체성은 단순하지 않았다.
You and your young master seemed to be lord and servant.
당신과 당신의 젊은 주인은 주인이자 하인처럼 보였습니다.
But in reality
하지만 실제로는
he treated her with even more respect.
그는 그녀를 더욱 존경심으로 대했습니다.
And before what happened in Luoyang,
그리고 뤄양에서 일어난 일이 있기 전에,
I saw you intrude in your Master's place.
나는 당신 이 주인의 자리에 침입하는 것을 보았습니다.
I knew that
나는 그것을 알고 있었다
after removing my mask,
마스크를 벗은 후,
after removing my mask.
마스크를 벗은 후.
But at that moment,
하지만 그 순간,
I was just defending in battle.
나는 단지 전투에서 방어하고 있었을 뿐입니다 .
How can you be sure
어떻게 확신할 수 있나요?
that I was my father's daughter?
내가 내 아버지의 딸이었다고?
When you were at Tong Pass,
통고개에 있었을 때,
risked his life
목숨을 걸고
to save General Cui
추이 장군을 구하기 위해
It may seem perfect to others.
다른 사람들에게는 완벽해 보일 수도 있습니다.
But after thinking about it,
그런데 곰곰히 생각해보니,
something seems to be wrong.
뭔가 잘못된 것 같습니다.
I finally guessed it.
드디어 짐작했습니다.
So you always knew.
그래서 당신은 항상 알고 있었죠.
You know what?
그거 알아?
I always wonder
난 항상 궁금해
If you are not from the Cui family,
Cui 가문 출신이 아닌 경우 ,
and I am not from the Li family.
저는 리 가문 출신이 아닙니다.
There will be
있을 것이다
Between us between us?
우리끼리 ?
Shiqi,
시치,
the identity is accurate.
신원은 정확합니다.
There is nothing that
그런 건 아무것도 없어
we can not do anything.
우리는 아무것도 할 수 없습니다.
You are sure.
당신은 확신합니다.
When the chaos began,
혼란이 시작되자,
I found this turbulent world
난 이 격동의 세상을 발견했어
there was no salvation.
구원은 없었습니다.
I couldn't see the people's sadness
사람들의 슬픔을 볼 수가 없었어
for the people.
사람들을 위해.
So I asked dad
그래서 아빠한테 물어봤는데
let me and the prince
나와 왕자님을 보자
south with our army.
우리 군대와 함께 남쪽으로.
Just in time,
딱 맞춰서,
it was just for
그것은 단지
restore peace to the world.
세계의 평화를 회복하십시오.
But I didn't expect that
하지만 난 그럴 줄은 몰랐어
to the Li family
리 가족에게
There was someone like you.
당신 같은 사람이 있었어요.
When we meet,
우리가 만날 때,
Did I cause you a lot of trouble?
내가 당신을 많이 힘들게 했나요?
Well, me too.
글쎄, 나도 마찬가지야.
Shiqi,
시치,
Did you think
생각 했습니까
if some day
만약 언젠가
can restore peace
평화를 회복할 수 있다
and peace for the world.
그리고 세계를 위한 평화.
Then,
그 다음에,
What kind of king does the world need?
세상에는 어떤 왕이 필요합니까?
Your father is already old.
당신의 아버지는 이미 늙었습니다.
O Lorde Xin eo Lorde Qi
O Lorde Xin eo Lorde Qi
They are not good rulers.
그들은 좋은 통치자가 아닙니다.
We still have the emperor's great-grandson.
우리에게는 아직 황제의 증손자가 있습니다.
I want to find him back
그 사람을 다시 찾고 싶어요
to ask the father
아버지에게 물어보려고
to name him crown prince.
그를 왕세자로 부르려고.
He has excellent intelligence,
지능이 뛰어나고,
and exceptional mentors.
그리고 뛰어난 멘토.
He definitely
그 사람은 확실히
he will definitely become a good king.
그는 반드시 좋은 왕이 될 것입니다.
And if you can't find the imperial great-grandson,
그리고 황실 증손자를 찾지 못한다면 ,
or if your father
아니면 네 아버지라면
don't want to name it
이름을 짓고 싶지 않아
to be the prince?
왕자가 되려고?
Let's run away.
달아나 자.
The world is at peace.
세상은 평화롭습니다.
And the emperor's great-grandson has already been found.
그리고 황제의 증손자는 이미 발견되었습니다.
Let's leave Xichang
시창을 떠나자
to live freely in Laolan Pass.
라오란 고개에서 자유롭게 살아보세요.
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
Even though I know it's not true,
사실이 아닌 걸 알면서도,
hear you say that
당신이 그런 말을 하는 걸 들어보세요
makes me happy.
나를 행복하게 해준다.
That day we agreed
그날 우리는 동의했습니다.
Let's go for a walk through Wonderland
이상한 나라를 산책하러 가자
and stroll through Wonderland.
그리고 이상한 나라를 산책해보세요.
It is a shame
부끄러운 일이다
the world is still in chaos.
세상은 여전히 ​​혼란에 빠져 있습니다.
Tomorrow,
내일,
everyone follows their own path.
모두가 자신의 길을 따릅니다.
That day will come.
그날이 올 것이다.
By the time,
그때쯤에는,
First let's see Wonderland.
먼저 원더랜드(Wonderland)를 보겠습니다.
Then we go to Laolan Pass.
그런 다음 Laolan Pass로 이동합니다.
Let's ride a horse together,
같이 말을 타자
and appreciate the wonder of the world.
그리고 세상의 경이로움을 감상해보세요.
He is well?
그는 잘 지내나요?
He is well.
그는 건강하다.
Tomorrow we will part.
내일 우리는 헤어질 것이다.
I don't know when we'll see each other again.
우리가 언제 다시 만날지 모르겠어요.
In that day,
그날,
I took what you love.
나는 당신이 좋아하는 것을 가져갔습니다.
Today,
오늘,
returned to the owner.
주인에게 돌아왔습니다.
Ying,
잉,
you and your child
당신과 당신의 아이
really grew up together?
정말 같이 자랐어?
I can see that you are particularly worried
유난히 걱정하고 계시는 걸 보니
with this subject.
이 주제로.
It is clear.
분명합니다.
When I first saw you two,
너희 둘을 처음 봤을 때,
you were so close.
당신은 너무 가까웠어요.
It made me uncomfortable.
그것은 나를 불편하게 만들었습니다.
Why do you even want to ask?
왜 묻고 싶나요?
The Young Master
젊은 마스터
is probably no longer in this world.
아마 이 세상에는 없을 것 같아요.
I just wanted to hear
그냥 듣고 싶었어
hear you explain to me.
당신이 나에게 설명하는 것을 들어보세요.
Then I won't have any suspicions.
그러면 나는 아무런 의심도 하지 않을 것이다.
After this,
금후,
I won't ask anymore.
더 이상 묻지 않겠습니다.
Young Master's real name
영 마스터의 본명은
É Liu Chengfeng.
에 리우 청펑(Liu Chengfeng).
He saved me when I was young.
그가 어렸을 때 나를 구해줬어요.
His parents died early.
그의 부모님은 일찍 돌아가셨습니다.
That's why,
그렇기 때문에,
he was adopted by his father.
그는 아버지에게 입양되었습니다.
When my mother was young,
어머니가 어렸을 때,
When he was young, it affected his health.
그가 어렸을 때 그것은 그의 건강에 영향을 미쳤습니다.
That's why after ten years of being married to my father,
그래서 아버지와 결혼한 지 10년 만에
she never had children.
그녀에게는 아이가 없었습니다.
But at that time,
그러나 그 당시,
his father was already a general on the border.
그의 아버지는 이미 국경의 장군이었습니다.
To control his father, the king insisted
왕은 아버지를 통제하기 위해 주장했습니다.
to give him another wife
그에게 다른 아내를 주려고
to give him another wife.
그에게 다른 아내를 주기 위해.
Later, my mother was determined
나중에 어머니는 결심하셨습니다.
to seek medical advice.
의학적 조언을 구합니다.
I was finally born.
나는 마침내 태어났다.
It is a shame
부끄러운 일이다
cannot satisfy the court.
법원을 만족시킬 수 없습니다 .
So my father lied to me saying that
그래서 아버지는 나에게 이렇게 거짓말을 하셨습니다.
he had a son
그에게는 아들이 있었어요
called Cui Lin, following tradition the Cui family gave its name,
추이린(Cui Lin)이라고 불리며, 추이(Cui) 가족이 전통에 따라 이름을 지었습니다.
to report to the court.
법원에 신고하려고 합니다.
I understood.
나는 이해했다.
Since then,
그때부터,
meu pai lutou em Yingzhou, em Yingzhou.
meu pai lutou em Yingzhou, em Yingzhou.
His mother fought with courage and died in the city.
그의 어머니는 용감하게 싸웠고 도시에서 죽었습니다.
The mother's position as the heroine.
주인공으로서의 어머니의 위치 .
The father enjoys the mother very much.
아버지는 어머니를 매우 좋아합니다.
And he never remarried.
그리고 그는 재혼하지 않았습니다.
Since then, my father
그 이후로 아버지는
raised me as a boy.
나를 소년으로 키웠어요.
But when I turn seven,
하지만 일곱 살이 되던 해,
I can no longer hide
더 이상 숨길 수 없어
my feminine side.
내 여성스러운 면.
So my father asked Liu Chengfeng
그래서 아버지는 Liu Chengfeng에게 물으셨습니다.
take my name, Cui Lin,
내 이름을 따오세요, 추이린(Cui Lin)
to hide
숨기려고
to prevent my girl identity
내 여자 정체성을 막기 위해
be exposed.
노출되다.
Since little,
어렸을 때부터,
the Young Master faced many dangers
Young Master는 많은 위험에 직면했습니다.
many dangers.
많은 위험.
Nobody knows his name
아무도 그의 이름을 모른다
nobody knew.
아무도 몰랐습니다.
Therefore, he became
그러므로 그는 되었다.
a shadow for me.
나에게 그림자.
We both grew up together.
우리 둘 다 함께 자랐습니다.
I considered him like an older brother.
나는 그를 형처럼 여겼다.
Naturally, we were closer
자연스럽게 우리는 더 가까워졌다.
than others.
다른 사람보다.
You consider him an older brother,
당신은 그를 형이라고 생각합니다.
but he doesn't think so.
하지만 그는 그렇게 생각하지 않습니다.
He is no longer with us.
그는 더 이상 우리와 함께 있지 않습니다.
Why do you care so much about this?
왜 이것에 그렇게 관심을 두나요?
Why does it always have to be about me?
왜 항상 나에 관한 것이어야 합니까?
And you?
당신은요?
And me?
그리고 나?
Mr. Gu's daughter,
구씨의 딸,
likes you a lot.
당신을 많이 좋아해요.
When we were in Xichang,
우리가 시창에 있을 때,
she came to the inn to give him a message.
그녀는 그에게 메시지를 전하기 위해 여관에 왔습니다 .
Won't you return her love?
그녀의 사랑을 돌려주지 않겠습니까 ?
What does Ms. GU feels about me what Ms. GU feels for me
GU 선생님은 나에 대해 어떻게 생각하시나요?
We're different.
우리는 다릅니다.
She is interested in me.
그녀는 나에게 관심이 있습니다.
But I have no interest in her.
하지만 나는 그녀에게 관심이 없습니다.
So I can only disappoint her.
그래서 나는 그녀를 실망시킬 수 밖에 없습니다.
Drinking and singing together
함께 마시고 노래부르기
when we think about life.
우리가 인생에 대해 생각할 때.
Shiqi,
시치,
Can you sing a song for me?
나를 위해 노래를 불러줄 수 있나요?
I don't know how to sing.
나는 노래하는 법을 모른다.
I can only hum a little
조금밖에 흥얼거릴 수 없어
to Laolan melody.
라오란 멜로디에 맞춰
Laolan's melody is also good.
Laolan의 멜로디도 좋습니다.
I want to listen.
나는 듣고 싶다.
These rural folk songs
이 시골 민요는
cannot be compared to the elegance of literature.
문학의 우아함과는 비교할 수 없습니다 .
It's a little rough.
조금 거칠다.
So please be patient.
그러니 인내심을 가지시기 바랍니다.
I don't mind.
나는 상관하지 않는다.
He is well.
그는 건강하다.
♪ The Laolan River has eighteen bends ♪ The Laolan River has 18 bends.
♪ 라오란강에는 18개의 굽이가 있습니다 ♪ 라오란강에는 18개의 굽이가 있습니다.
♪ The first bend in the river is Yinsong ♪
♪ 강의 첫 번째 굴곡은 인송입니다 ♪
♪ The fish in Yinsong is fat and heavy ♪
♪인송의 생선은 살이 많고 무겁습니다 ♪
♪ But you can't compare ♪ The girl who opened the window.
♪ 하지만 비교할 수는 없어 ♪ 창문을 연 소녀.
♪ The Laolan River has 18 bends ♪ ♪ The Laolan River has eighteen bends ♪
♪ 라오란강에는 18개의 굽이가 있습니다 ♪
Did I sing badly?
내가 노래를 잘 못 불렀나?
It's a little out of tune.
조금 어긋나네요.
So why did you ask me to sing?
그럼 왜 나한테 노래를 불러달라고 했나?
But it sounds good.
하지만 좋은 것 같습니다.
Serious?
심각한?
So I will sing seriously this time.
그래서 이번에는 진지하게 노래하겠습니다.
He is well.
그는 건강하다.
Now I'm going to get up and sing seriously.
이제 일어나서 진지하게 노래할 거예요.
♪ The Laolan River has 18 bends ♪ The Laolan River has 18 bends.
♪ 라오란강에는 18개의 굽이가 있습니다 ♪ 라오란강에는 18개의 굽이가 있습니다.
♪ The first bend in the river is Yinsong ♪
♪ 강의 첫 번째 굴곡은 인송입니다 ♪
♪ The fish in Yinsong is fat and heavy ♪
♪인송의 생선은 살이 많고 무겁습니다 ♪
♪ But they don't compare to that girl's beautiful eyes.
♪ 하지만 그 소녀의 아름다운 눈과는 비교가 안 돼요 .
♪ The river bends are eighteen ♪ ♪ The Laolan River has 18 bends ♪
♪ 강의 굽이는 18개입니다 ♪ ♪ 라오란강의 굽이는 18개입니다 ♪
♪ The second bend in the river is ♪ It's a beautiful coast.
♪ 강의 두 번째 굴곡은 ♪ 아름다운 해안이에요.
Ying.
잉.
♪ Between the moonlight and your vows ♪
♪ 달빛과 당신의 맹세 사이 ♪
♪ To fall into my heart ♪
♪ 내 마음에 빠지게 ♪
♪ Telling me about your eternity ♪
♪당신의 영원에 대해 말해주세요 ♪
If you don't wake up,
안 일어나면,
I go...
나 간다...
I'll kiss you.
키스할게요.
♪ Who can make me forget everything ♪
♪ 누가 나로 하여금 모든 것을 잊게 만들 수 있나요 ♪
I'm really going to kiss you.
나 진짜 너한테 키스할 거야.
♪ Tomorrow ♪
♪ 내일 ♪
♪ We search together ♪
♪함께 검색해요♪
♪ You took me ♪ Through the night.
♪ 당신은 나를 데려갔습니다 ♪ 밤새도록.
♪ The shattered world brings with it ♪
♪ 산산이 부서진 세상이 가져온다 ♪
♪ You gave me a firm conviction ♪
♪당신은 나에게 확고한 신념을 주었습니다 ♪
(Lyrics) In adversity, the only light is love ♪ That never dies ♪
(가사) 역경 속에 빛은 오직 사랑뿐이야 ♪ 그건 절대 죽지 않아 ♪
♪ Every breakup I endured ♪
♪ 이별마다 참아냈어 ♪
♪ Waiting for you every second ♪ ♪ Every second I look for you ♪
♪ 매 순간 당신을 기다리고 있어요 ♪ ♪ 매 순간 당신을 찾아요 ♪
♪ I'm not afraid of obstacles ♪ ♪ I want to love until the end ♪
♪ 난 장애물이 두렵지 않아 ♪ ♪ 끝까지 사랑하고 싶어 ♪
♪ change ♪
♪ 변화 ♪
♪ Crossing the night ♪ ♪ I will cross the danger ♪
♪ 밤을 건너 ♪ ♪ 위험을 건너리라 ♪
♪ I make my heart burn with passion ♪
♪나는 내 마음을 열정으로 불타게 만든다 ♪
♪ You're by my side ♪
♪ 당신은 내 곁에 있어요 ♪
♪ Arranging towards our eternal vow ♪
♪영원한 맹세를 위한 준비 ♪
♪ Growing up stubborn ♪ Can't accept it.
♪ 완고하게 자라는 중 ♪ 받아들일 수 없어.
♪ Passing through destiny, ♪ carrying persistence ♪
♪ 운명을 헤쳐 나가고, ♪ 끈기를 갖고 ♪
♪ And don't let go ♪ ♪ Standing by your side ♪
♪ 그리고 놓지 마세요 ♪ ♪ 옆에 서 있어요 ♪
♪ In this suffering ♪ ♪ I finish painting the world in my hands ♪
♪ 이 고통 속에서 ♪ ♪ 나는 내 손으로 세상을 그린다 ♪
♪ To protect this eternal love ♪
♪ 이 영원한 사랑을 지키기 위해 ♪
♪ Based on the faith you gave me ♪
♪당신이 나에게 주신 믿음을 바탕으로 ♪
♪ I'm not afraid of obstacles or thorns ♪ We hold on until the end.
♪ 장애물도 가시도 두렵지 않아요 ♪ 우리는 끝까지 버틴다.
♪ Going through the night with you ♪ By your side ♪
♪당신과 함께 밤을 보내요 ♪ 당신 곁에서 ♪
♪ Taking care of our belief ♪
♪우리의 믿음을 돌보세요 ♪
♪ Holding your hand ♪ ♪ I'm holding your hand until the end ♪
♪ 손을 잡아요 ♪ ♪ 끝까지 손을 잡고 있어요 ♪
♪ In defense of eternal love ♪
♪영원한 사랑을 지키기 위해 ♪
♪ We all spent the night together ♪
♪우리는 모두 함께 밤을 보냈습니다 ♪
Shiqi,
시치,
let's go.
갑시다.
♪ Unchanged ♪
♪ 변함없음 ♪
♪ A predestined relationship ♪
♪ 예정된 인연 ♪
♪ But roles that shouldn't always be ♪
♪하지만 항상 있어서는 안되는 역할 ♪
♪ Unlimited Patience ♪
♪ 무한한 인내 ♪
♪ Wishing to escape this conflict ♪
♪이 갈등에서 벗어나고 싶다 ♪
♪ The mutual trust we have ♪
♪ 우리가 갖고 있는 상호 신뢰 ♪
♪ To cut resentment and hatred. ♪
♪ 원한과 증오를 없애기 위해. ♪
♪ This colorful array in the sky ♪
♪ 하늘에 떠 있는 이 다채로운 배열 ♪
♪ Just you and me ♪
♪ 너와 나만 ♪
♪ You are the beginning of anticipation ♪
♪당신은 기대의 시작입니다 ♪
♪ Heartbroken ♪
♪ 상심했어요 ♪
♪ You are the final answer ♪
♪ 당신이 최종 답입니다 ♪
♪ I don't regret it, I don't regret it ♪
♪후회하지 않아, 후회하지 않아♪
♪ My unspoken words are written on parchment ♪
♪내가 말하지 않은 말은 양피지에 적혀있습니다 ♪
♪ Imitators who follow one after the other ♪
♪ 잇달아 따라오는 모방자들 ♪
♪ You are the only one ♪
♪당신은 유일한 사람입니다 ♪
♪ The heart knows in secret ♪
♪ 마음은 비밀을 알고 있습니다 ♪
♪ You are a persistent longing ♪
♪당신은 끈질긴 그리움이에요 ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ 영원히 ♪
♪ I'm willing to leave this world for you ♪ ♪ I want to leave this world for you ♪
♪ 나는 당신을 위해 이 세상을 기꺼이 떠나고 싶습니다 ♪ ♪ 나는 당신을 위해 이 세상을 떠나고 싶습니다 ♪
♪ I have no regrets in this life ♪
♪나는 이번 생에 후회하지 않는다 ♪
♪ You are the beginning of anticipation ♪
♪당신은 기대의 시작입니다 ♪
♪ Heartbroken ♪
♪ 상심했어요 ♪
♪ You are the final answer ♪
♪ 당신이 최종 답입니다 ♪
♪ I don't regret it, I don't regret it ♪
♪후회하지 않아, 후회하지 않아♪
♪ My unspoken words are written on parchment ♪
♪내가 말하지 않은 말은 양피지에 적혀있습니다 ♪
♪ Imitators who follow one after the other ♪
♪ 잇달아 따라오는 모방자들 ♪
♪ You are the only one ♪
♪당신은 유일한 사람입니다 ♪
♪ The heart knows ♪
♪ 마음은 알고 있어요 ♪
♪ You are the eternal longing ♪
♪당신은 영원한 그리움입니다 ♪
♪ I will never back down ♪
♪나는 결코 물러서지 않을 것이다 ♪
♪ Never apart no matter what ♪
♪ 무슨 일이 있어도 절대 헤어지지 마세요 ♪
Heaven and earth can testify to our love. Witness our love.
하늘과 땅이 우리의 사랑을 증거할 수 있습니다. 우리의 사랑을 목격하십시오.